Harpreet Kaur

Brampton ON, L7A 4R7 | 437-998-2106 | hkaur108@hotmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/harpreet-kaur-7544a0300

WEB DEVELOPER

Project Portfolio: https://hkaur108.github.io/portfolio/

Self-motivated IT Developer with education in computer science and experience in technical support. Analytical problem solver with a keen curiosity, a passion for learning and a strong attention to detail. Open communicator and collaborator works well in a fast-paced diverse team environment.

KEY SKILLS

Technology Support | Customer Service | Analytical Problem Solving | Troubleshooting Creative Design | Cross-Functional Collaboration | Leadership | Due Diligence

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5, CCS3, BOOTSTRAP5, Javascript, and REACT, JQuery, TypeScript, Git Bash, Linux.
- Currently learning Node.js, mongoose DB and SQL to create full stack websites

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Database: MySQL, MongooseDb.

Networking: TCP/IP, FTP, VPN, Ethereal & Wireshark

Operating System: Windows, Solaris, UNIX, Linux, Active Directory, Windows Server 2016.

Programming Language: CSS,React,JQuery,Typescript,Git, Javascript, Assembly, UNIX shell, HTML

Collaboration Software: Exchange Server, SharePoint, Office Communications Server, Skype, Jabber, Slack

WORK EXPERIENCE

AlarmForce Industries Inc., Toronto, ON **Technical Support Associate**

March 2022 - May 2024

Answered inbound calls pertaining to technical issues related to the alarm system; troubleshoot issues with video devices and security systems and booked technicians if required.

- Used Live video assistance to remotely access customer's device to assist customer in troubleshooting.
- Provided reset password links to customers not able to login to the app or the online portal.
- Follow up with the customer to check whether they are satisfied by the technician's job on site and then
 document accounts with the information provided by the customer if required another appointment is
 booked.

Skanna Security and Investigations, Scarborough, ON **Loss Prevention Officer**

June 2018 - February 2022

Worked as a Loss prevention officer handling front desk responsibilities and monitoring video surveillance.

Scanned employees coming from the warehouse via metal detector.

• Made entries in the portal for the trailers coming and leaving the yard; fully trained on Gatehouse roles and responsibilities.

Convergys India Ltd, Gurugram Haryana

April 2014 - August 2017

Technical Support Associate

Answered inbound calls related to handset and network problems; opened and escalated to 2nd level support team if required.

- Followed the call flow guide to properly answer calls and resolve issues.
- Connected calls to the correct department in case the client wants to purchase any additional products and services.
- Maintained the proper documentation of the call and retrieved data accordingly.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Development Bootcamp | Udemy
Comptia A+ Certification | Comptia
AlarmForce Certified Technician | Sponsored by AlarmForce

EDUCATION

Cyber Security and Computer Forensics Post Graduate Diploma Lambton College

Bachelor of Computer Applications, B.C.A.Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi, India